iqnavigator.com 2016-10-12

# Privacy Policy - IQNavigator

### BACKGROUND

IQNavigator provides services procurement and payment automation solutions for Global 2000 enterprises. As part of its process management services, IQNavigator obtains and processes Personal Data on behalf of customers and their services suppliers. In addition, IQNavigator obtains Personal Data of website visitors who request to receive marketing materials via email. This Privacy Policy describes IQNavigator’s commitment to privacy and the procedures and policies to protect all the Personal Data in IQNavigator’s possession.

Under this Privacy Policy and the embodied procedures and policies, IQNavigator complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. IQNavigator has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement, as described below. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view IQNavigator’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

This Privacy Policy was last changed on June 2013.

### DEFINITIONS

Personal Data refers to any information that is identifiable to specific individuals or by which specific individuals can be identified, such as name, identification numbers, email address, mailing address, phone numbers, or other personal characteristics or attributes.  
Personal Data does not include information that is previously publicly available or is anonymous statistical information that is not identifiable to a specific individual.

Data Subjects refers to the individuals to whom the Personal Data refers.

Data Controller refers to the owner of the data, which in most cases is the customer or their services supplier. When the Data Controller is an IQNavigator customer or their supplier, IQNavigator performs the role of Data Processor and is obligated to uphold the customer’s or supplier’s information confidentiality and privacy policies.

Customer Confidential refers to non-public information that is proprietary to our customers or their services suppliers.

### PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

IQNavigator is committed to individual privacy and recognizes its responsibility for protecting the Personal Data in its possession and care. The IQNavigator Privacy Policy is embodied in the following principles:

**Notice:** Data Subjects will be notified at the time of data collection regarding what Personal Data is collected, how it will be used, and to whom it will be disclosed, either directly by IQNavigator or by the Data Controller, as appropriate. This Privacy Policy will be published prominently on IQNavigator’s website as well as via communications with Data Subjects, such as upon login to the IQNavigator software applications. This policy may change from time to time, in which case appropriate notifications will be placed in the IQNavigator software applications.

**Access:** Data Subjects will be granted access to the Personal Data related to them, and will be able to submit corrections to the information where it is believed to be inaccurate (see “Inquiries” below). Corrections will be subject to verification and acceptance by the Data Controller.

**Data integrity:** IQNavigator collects, retains and uses only relevant Personal Data necessary for conducting business. IQNavigator will take steps to ensure that the Personal Data is accurate and current.

**Onward Transfer and Choice:** We will not transfer Personal Data to third parties, other than the Data Controller and third parties who participate with us or our customers and their suppliers in performing the agreed-upon process management services. All such parties agree to maintain appropriate procedures to safeguard the Personal Data and use it only for the purposes described in the collection notice and as the Data Controller directs.

**Security:** IQNavigator will treat all Personal Data as confidential to the Data Subject and to the Data Controller, and will maintain internal procedures and security safeguards designed to prevent inappropriate disclosure, misuse, or alteration of Personal Data. IQNavigator personnel are responsible for protecting Personal Data and other Customer Confidential information, are trained in the applicable policies, and are expected to adhere to the procedures and intent of this Privacy Policy.

**Enforcement:** Data Subjects who believe that their Personal Data was not handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy should contact IQNavigator’s Privacy Officer (see “Inquiries” below), who will conduct an investigation and report their findings to the Data Subject. European Union (EU) or Switzerland residents may also make use of the appropriate Data Protection Authorities; IQNavigator will cooperate with EU or Swiss Data Protection Authorities to investigate and resolve complaints, including complying with any resulting advice given by the Data Protection Authorities.

### POLICY PRACTICES

**Information Collected**  
IQNavigator receives and stores nonpublic Personal Data and other Customer Confidential information from several sources in the normal course of business, including:

  * Identification and contact information from customers, their services suppliers, and the Data Subjects themselves.
  * Business process information (such as regarding services procurement and payment processes) through the usage of the IQNavigator applications and communications among customer users and their services suppliers, the Data Subjects, IQNavigator users, and third-party users.
  * Transaction and information system usage information from IQNavigator applications, IQNavigator websites, other contacts with IQNavigator, and third parties.

**Why This Information Is Collected**  
IQNavigator uses this nonpublic Personal Data and other Customer Confidential information for the purposes of:

  * Identifying the Data Subjects and associating their various authorized role(s) and preferences
  * Contacting and notifying Data Subjects of appropriate process events and data changes
  * Efficiently and accurately performing the process management services, including tasks as directed or authorized by the Data Controller.
  * Improve existing services and design new services

Consequently, the Personal Data collected is generally contact information, identification information, and process-related transaction information.

**How This Information Is Used**  
IQNavigator uses Personal Data only for the purposes for which it was collected as described above.

In the normal course of business, Personal Data and Customer Confidential information is processed by IQNavigator and via third parties who are contracted to uphold this Privacy Policy and any additional customer obligations. Personal Data may also be transferred to the Data Controller and their authorized agents in the course of performing the process management services.

In addition, IQNavigator will perform legitimate and relevant tasks as directed or authorized by the Data Controller.

**Information Security**  
Personal Data in IQNavigator’s possession is protected by its Information Systems Security Policy, which is designed to prevent unauthorized disclosure, misuse, or alteration of Personal Data. The Information Systems Security Policy includes confidentiality procedures applicable to all IQNavigator personnel, security requirements for physical and electronic security, and compliance policies and procedures for information handling. All IQNavigator personnel are required to acknowledge understanding of the Information Systems Security Policy, and adherence is enforced.

**Inquiries**  
To inquire about any aspect of this Privacy Policy, Personal Data held, or uses of the Personal Data, please contact the IQNavigator Privacy Officer via email at iqprivacy@iqnavigator.com, via telephone at +1-303-563-1500, or via mail to IQNavigator at 6465 Greenwood Plaza Boulevard, Suite 800, Centennial Colorado 80111 USA.

For inquiries from Data Subjects about their Personal Data, IQNavigator will forward the inquiries to the appropriate Data Controller (the customer or supplier who owns the data) and assist with resolving the inquiry, including providing access to the Personal Data and correcting any errors in cooperation with the Data Controller.  
  
IQNavigator has certified its compliance with the Safe Harbor requirements and has registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor website at<http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

**Privacy Shield Commitment**  
IQN has committed to self-certification under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and if there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To view the list of companies who have committed to to the Privacy Shield self certification [click here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

**Alternative Dispute Resolution(ADR)**  
IQN is committed to investigating and resolving all unresolved data privacy complaints in a timely manner.  As such if IQN is unable to resolve a complaint to the satisfaction of all parties, IQN will provide free of charge access to an Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) provider.

To learn more about IQN’s ADR, JAMS, [click here](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield).

### COOKIE POLICY FOR IQNAVIGATOR

**What Are Cookies?  
**As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or ‘break’ certain elements of the sites functionality.

For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on [HTTP Cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)…

******How We Use Cookies**  
We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

**Disabling Cookies  
**You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

**Cookies We Set**  
This site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.

From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.

When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.

******Third Party Cookies**  
In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official [Google Analytics ](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)page.

From time to time we test new features and make subtle changes to the way that the site is delivered. When we are still testing new features these cookies may be used to ensure that you receive a consistent experience whilst on the site whilst ensuring we understand which optimizations our users appreciate the most.

As we sell products it’s important for us to understand statistics about how many of the visitors to our site actually make a purchase and as such this is the kind of data that these cookies will track. This is important to you as it means that we can accurately make business predictions that allow us to monitor our advertising and product costs to ensure the best possible price.

The Google AdSense service we use to serve advertising uses a DoubleClick cookie to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times that a given ad is shown to you.

For more information on Google AdSense see the official [Google AdSense privacy FAQ](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/3394713?hl=en).

Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase.

We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIN, Google+, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

******More Information**  
Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you aren’t sure whether you need or not it’s usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case it does interact with one of the features you use on our site. However if you are still looking for more information then you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods.  
Email: [marketing@iqn.com](mailto:marketing@iqn.com)
